Finding aid for the Bonnie Cashin Collection of Fashion, Theater, and Film Costume Design LSC.0440
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Accessory Designs, ca. 1955 - 1987; 97 folders
  - Headcover Designs, ca. 1950s - 1978; 3 folders
    - Rough illustrations of Cashin's design ideas, including headcovers., ca. 1950s - 1970s; 20 illustrations (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Prototype hats designed by Cashin., ca. 1960s; 7 hats (Box 305, Folder 1)
  - Coach; Handbags and Related Accessories, 1962 - 1975; 3 oversize boxes and 5 folders
    This subseries contains documentation of Bonnie Cashin's accessory designs for manufacturer Coach. The series is particularly rich in promotional material as well as preliminary sketches of handbag designs. Several prototypes and manufactured examples of her handbag designs are also included. All illustrations, writings, and brochures by Bonnie Cashin.
    - Cashin's illustrations of handbag designs for Coach., Mid-1960s; 20 illustrations (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Cashin's pencil illustrations of handbag designs for Coach., 1962 - 1964; 18 illustrations (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Reprints of Coach brochure covers featuring art by Cashin., ca. 1962 - 1972; 15 pages (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's memos and illustrations of "Cashin Carry" handbag designs for Coach., ca. 1964; 7 pages (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's illustrations of handbag designs for Coach (handbags only)., ca. 1964; 12 illustrations (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustrations of handbag designs for Coach (handbags shown on models)., ca. 1964 - 1968; 10 illustrations (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of handbag designs for Coach., Spring 1971; 10 illustrations (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs and swatch of Cashin's trademark striped lining., ca. 1962; 9 illustrations (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., 1962 - 1972; 32 illustrations (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., ca. 1965; 33 illustrations (Box 177, Folder 3)
    - Line list of Cashin's handbag designs with rough design illustrations., Spring - Summer 1966; 5 pages (Box 177, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., ca. 1968; 25 illustrations (Box 177, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., ca. 1970; 13 illustrations (Box 177, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., February 17, 1970; 36 illustrations (Box 177, Folder 7)
    - Memos, essays, correspondence, and promotional materials regarding Cashin's accessory designs., ca. 1962 - 1970; 51 pages (Box 178, Folder 1)
    - Promotional material and press releases regarding Cashin's handbag designs., 1965 - 1973; 28 pages (Box 178, Folder 2)
    - File folder for Coach documents., 1960s; 1 folder (Box 178, Folder 3)
    - Clippings regarding Cashin's handbag designs., March 2, 1962 - May 19, 1967; 4 pages (Box 178, Folder 4)
    - Photostats of Cashin's design illustrations used for Coach brochures., ca. 1964 - 1967; 7 illustrations (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - Publicity photographs of Cashin's handbag designs., April 3, 1962 - Ca. 1968; 3 photographs (Box 178, Folder 6)
    - Coach brochure featuring Cashin's handbag design illustrations and mission statement., ca. 1964; 2 brochures (Box 178, Folder 7)
    - Coach brochure featuring Cashin's handbag design illustrations, mission statement, and line list., Spring 1964; 1 brochure (Box 178, Folder 8)
    - Coach brochure featuring Cashin's handbag design illustrations, mission statement, and line list., Spring-Summer 1965; 1 brochure (Box 178, Folder 9)
    - Coach brochure featuring Cashin's handbag design illustrations, mission statement, and line list., Fall 1965; 1 brochure (Box 178, Folder 10)
    - Coach brochure featuring Cashin's handbag design illustrations, mission statement, and line list., Fall 1967; 1 brochure (Box 178, Folder 11)
    - Coach brochure featuring Cashin's handbag design illustrations, mission statement, and line list., Spring 1968; 1 brochure (Box 178, Folder 12)
    - Coach brochure featuring Cashin's handbag design illustrations, mission statement, and line list., Fall 1969; 1 brochure (Box 178, Folder 13)
    - Coach brochure featuring Cashin's handbag design illustrations, mission statement, and line list., Fall 1970; 1 brochure (Box 178, Folder 14)
    - Line list of Cashin's handbag designs., Spring 1974; 1 page (Box 178, Folder 15)
    - Coach catalogs featuring Cashin's handbag designs in production after termination of her design contract., Fall 1974 - Winter 1987; 7 catalogs (Box 178, Folder 16)
    - Promotional material following termination of Cashin's design contract., September 21, 1973 - February 1975; 8 pages; 1 folder (Box 178, Folder 17)
    - Clippings regarding Cashin's handbag designs in production after termination of her design contract., ca. 1974 - 1996; 13 clippings; 1 pamphlet (Box 178, Folder 18)
    - Prototype leather and snakeskin "shopping bag" designs and wallet designed by Cashin; very poor condition., ca. 1962; 4 handbags; 1 wallet (Box 307, Folder 1)
    - "Hero Lunchbox" handbag designed by Cashin., 1964; 1 handbag (Box 308, Folder 1)
    - Leather flask and plastic bottle insert designed by Cashin., 1964; 2 items (Box 309, Folder 1)
    - Coach handbags designed by Cashin: Pink leather "Closed Shopping Bag, Dinky; black crushed cowhide "Double Entry" fall 1967; black leather "Mail Sac"; black leather "Double Entry Large.", ca. 1964 - 1968; 4 handbags (Box 310, Folder 1)
  - Crescendoe-Superb; Gloves, 1970 - 1974; 6 folders
    This subseries contains documentation of Bonnie Cashin's glove designs for manufacturer Crescendoe-Superb. The subseries includes Cashin's design illustrations, memos, and essays regarding glove design as well as slides featuring her designs and a selection of prototype or sample gloves. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Memos, sketches, and essays re. Cashin's glove designs for Crescendoe-Superb., 1970 - 1974; 20 pages (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of glove designs for Crescendoe-Superb., ca. 1970; 10 illustrations (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's illustrations of glove designs for Crescendoe-Superb., ca. 1970; 6 illustrations (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Slides; Cashin's glove designs for Crescendoe-Superb, modeled in Manhattan., June 1970 (Fall 1970); 14 slides (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Slides; Cashin's glove designs for Crescendoe-Superb, modeled in Cashin's studio., July 1970 (Fall 1970 Collection); 39 slides (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Prototype and sample gloves designed by Cashin., ca. 1972; 25 single prototype gloves; 5 pairs (Box 306, Folder 1)
  - Meyers; Handbags, 1975 - 1979; 2 oversize boxes and 2 folders
    This subseries contains documentation of Bonnie Cashin's accessory designs for manufacturer Meyers. The subseries is particularly rich in Cashin's notes, line lists, and preliminary sketches regarding her handbag designs. All illustrations by Bonnie Cashin contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's illustrations of handbag designs for Meyers., ca. 1975 - 1978; 10 illustrations (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations of handbag designs for Meyers., ca. 1975 - 1978; 32 illustrations (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Notes, correspondence, and swatches for Cashin's handbag designs., 1975 - 1979; 18 pages (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's illustrations of handbag and accessory designs., 1975 - 1979; 9 illustrations (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's rough sketches and notes regarding handbag and accessory designs., 1975 - 1978; 23 illustrations (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - Photostats of Cashin's illustrations of handbag designs used for promotion of Meyers collections., 1975 - 1978; 6 illustrations (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - Line lists of Cashin's handbag designs., 1975 - 1978; 9 pages; 3 brochures (Box 179, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs; folder 1 of 2., June 1975; 27 illustrations (Box 179, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs; folder 2 of 2., 1970s; 18 illustrations (Box 179, Folder 7)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., Fall 1975; 13 illustrations (Box 179, Folder 8)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., ca. 1975 - 1976; 12 illustrations (Box 179, Folder 9)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., February 3 - February 12, 1976; 11 illustrations (Box 179, Folder 10)
    - Swatches, notes, and brochure with line list of Cashin's handbag designs., Fall 1976; 3 pages; 1 brochure (Box 179, Folder 11)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., August 19, 1976; 11 illustrations (Box 179, Folder 12)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., September 1, 1976; 6 illustrations (Box 179, Folder 13)
    - Brochure and line list of Cashin's handbag designs., Spring 1977; 15 pages; 1 brochure (Box 179, Folder 14)
    - Notes regarding materials for Cashin's handbag designs., January 1977; 7 pages (Box 179, Folder 15)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., February 1977; 10 illustrations (Box 180, Folder 1)
    - Brochure with line list of Cashin's handbag designs., Fall 1977; 1 brochure (Box 180, Folder 2)
    - Notes, sketches, and brochure regarding Cashin's handbag designs., August 8, 1977; 10 pages; 1 brochure (Box 180, Folder 3)
    - Notes, sketches and brochure for Cashin's handbag designs for Liberty of London collection., August 1977; 6 pages; 1 brochure (Box 180, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustrations of handbag designs for Liberty of London collection., September 1977; 17 illustrations (Box 180, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of handbag designs for Liberty of London collection., November 1977; 10 illustrations (Box 180, Folder 6)
    - Notes, sketches, and brochure with line list of Cashin's handbag designs., February 1978 - Fall 1978; 25 pages; 1 brochure (Box 180, Folder 7)
    - Line list of Cashin's handbag designs., Fall 1978; 16 pages (Box 180, Folder 8)
    - Notes, sketches, and line list of Cashin's handbag designs., October 1978 - Spring 1979; 29 pages (Box 180, Folder 9)
    - Notes and sketches of Cashin's handbag designs., February - Fall 1979; 15 pages (Box 180, Folder 10)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., February 23, 1979; 14 illustrations (Box 180, Folder 11)
    - Cashin's rough sketches of handbag designs., ca. 1979; 9 illustrations (Box 180, Folder 12)
  - D. Klein: Totes and Umbrellas, 1977 - 1979; 1 oversize box and 2 folders
    This subseries contains documentation of Bonnie Cashin's tote bag and umbrella designs for manufacturer D. Klein. The subseries includes Cashin's design illustrations, memos, and essays regarding accessory design as well as one example of a tote bag. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Notes and correspondence regarding Cashin's tote bag and umbrella designs for D. Klein., 1977 - 1978; 33 pages (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's labels and logo ideas for D. Klein., 1977; 41 pages (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's rough illustrations and clippings regarding umbrella and tote bag designs for D. Klein., 1977; 36 pages (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Canvas swatches for Cashin's tote bag designs for D. Klein., 1977; 3 swatches (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustrations of tote bag designs for D. Klein. Folder 1 of 2., March 14, 1977 and undated; 11 illustrations (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's umbrella design illustrations for D. Klein. Folder 2 of 2., March - September 1977; 11 illustrations (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's tote bag design illustrations for D. Klein Spring 1978 collection. Folder 1 of 2., October 20, 1977; 14 illustrations (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Cashin's umbrella design illustrations for D. Klein's Spring 1978 collection. Folder 2 of 2., October 27, 1977; 4 illustrations (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Cashin's tote bag design illustrations for D. Klein's Fall 1978 collection. Folder 1 of 2., April 10, 1978; 17 illustrations (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Cashin's illustrations of umbrella designs for D. Klein's Fall 1978 collection. Folder 2 of 2., April 10, 1978; 7 illustrations (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Cashin's illustrations of tote bags for D. Klein's Spring 1979 collection. Folder 1 of 2., September 25, 1978; 15 illustrations (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Cashin's umbrella design illustrations D. Klein's Spring 1979 collection. Folder 2 of 2., 1978; 7 illustrations (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Cashin's illustrations of tote bag designs for D. Klein's Fall 1979 collection., 6 illustrations (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Slides; Private showing of Cashin's tote and umbrella designs for D. Klein, in Cashin's studio., May 1975; 8 slides (Box 132, Folder 18)
    - Totebag designed by Cashin., ca. 1977; 1 tote bag (Box 310, Folder 1)
  - Bonnie Cashin Collection; Belts and Handbags, ca. 1960s - January 15, 1980; 5 folders
    This subseries contains documentation of various accessory designs by Bonnie Cashin. The subseries is rich in both Cashin's original illustrations and sample hats and belts. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's illustrations of handbag and wallet designs for unproduced "Bonnie Cashin Collection.", August 22, 1978 - January 15, 1980; 13 illustrations (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations of belts and belted handbag designs for unproduced "Bonnie Cashin Collection.", ca. 1978-1980; 12 illustrations (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Suede and leather string and cummerbund belts designed by Cashin., ca. 1970s; 8 belts (Box 312, Folder 1)
    - Belts and head wraps designed by Cashin., ca. 1970s; 3 belts; 3 head wraps (Box 313, Folder 1)
    - "Bag hats" and shower cap hat designed by Cashin., ca. 1960s; 9 hats (Box 314, Folder 1)
  - Sketches (Accessory Designs), ca. 1955; 1 folder
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's illustrations of accessory designs. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's rough illustrations of accessory designs., ca. 1955; 3 illustrations (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Aris: Knit Gloves and Hats, December 15, 1976; 2 folders
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's illustrations of hat and glove designs for manufacturer Aris. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's illustrations of glove, hat, and scarf designs., December 15, 1976; 9 illustrations (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Cashin's illustrations of glove and hat designs., December 15, 1976; 4 illustrations (Box 188, Folder 1)
- Alex Gropper: Gropper Leather Wear, 1978 - 1979; 1 oversize box
  This series contains Bonnie Cashin's record of leather clothing designed for Alex Gropper. The series largely consists of Cashin's design illustrations. All materials contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Leather Separates, December 1978 - July 1979; 1 oversize box
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's illustrations of leather separates designed for manufacturer Alex Gropper. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Alex Gropper. Folder 1 of 2., December 1978 - February 1979; 14 illustrations (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Alex Gropper. Folder 2 of 2., December 1978 - February 1979; 16 illustrations (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Alex Gropper., February 1979; 22 illustrations (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Alex Gropper., ca. 1979; 4 illustrations (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Alex Gropper., ca. 1979; 12 illustrations (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Alex Gropper, Spring 1980 collection., July 1979; 5 illustrations (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Swatches, 1979; 1 folder
    This subseries contains swatches of leather selected by Bonnie Cashin for use in her ready-to-wear designs for manufacturer Alex Gropper.
    - Suede swatches for Cashin's Fall 1979 ready-to-wear collection for Alex Gropper., 2 swatches (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - India Collection, December 1978 - August 1979; 3 folders
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for manufacturer Alex Gropper titled "India Collection." The subseries also includes swatches of materials selected by Cashin for use in this collection. All illustrations by Bonnie Cashin contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Alex Gropper., December 1978 - January 17, 1979; 18 illustrations (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Color and leather swatches for Cashin's ready-to-wear designs for Alex Gropper, Spring 1979 - 1980 collection., February 1979 - August 1979; 6 items (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Alex Gropper, with swatches (reduced copies)., August 2, 1979; 7 illustrations (Box 44, Folder 10)
- Russell Taylor Ready-to-Wear, 1978 - 1984; 19 oversize boxes
  This series contains Bonnie Cashin's record of her ready-to-wear designs for manufacturer Russell Taylor. The series is particularly rich in Cashin's design illustrations and also includes publicity photographs of her designs. The series is subdivided by two primary collections, "Weatherwear" and "Cashin Country," and by headcover and outerwear designs which bear a Russell Taylor designation only. All materials contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Slides (Russell Taylor Ready-to-Wear), 1978-1979; 3 folders
    - Fashion show of Cashin's ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, including Cashin Country and Weatherwear divisions., 1978; 111 slides (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - Fashion shows of Cashin's ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, including Cashin Country and Weatherwear divisions., Fall 1978; 124 slides (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - Fashion show of Cashin's ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor., May 1979; 20 slides (Box 133, Folder 9)
  - Headcover Designs, ca. 1950s - 1978; 3 folders
    - Cashin's illustrations of headcover designs for Russell Taylor., February 22, 1978 and undated; 3 illustrations (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Outerwear Designs, December 29, 1977 - November 16, 1978; 1 oversize box
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's illustrations of outerwear designs for manufacturer Russell Taylor. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, Early Spring collection., 1978; 34 illustrations (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, Fall 1978 collection., December 29, 1977 - March 1978; 30 illustrations (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, Fall 1978 collection., December 29, 1977 - March 1978; 38 illustrations (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustration of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor., May 21, 1978; 1 illustration (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, Spring 1979 collection., August 1978; 31 illustrations (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, Summer collection., November 16, 1978; 3 illustrations (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Cashin Country, ca. 1978 - June 4, 1982; 9 oversize boxes
    This subseries contains documentation of Bonnie Cashin's ready-to-wear designs for manufacturer Russell Taylor. The subseries is particularly rich in Cashin's design illustrations and also includes swatches and photographs featuring her designs. All original illustrations by Bonnie Cashin contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Press material for Cashin Country collection designed by Cashin., 1978 - 1982; 101 pages (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, jersey shirt styles, A - G., 1978; 7 illustrations (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, pant and skirt styles, B - F., 1978; 7 illustrations (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, numbered Levine knits, 1 - 10., 1978; 11 illustrations (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, numbered Cashin Country 1- 23., December 1978; 23 illustrations (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, numbered 24 - 54., January 1979; 16 illustrations (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, numbered 40 - 57., 1979; 19 illustrations (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, numbered 58 - 75., March 1979; 18 illustrations (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, numbered 76 - 79., April 1979; 4 illustrations (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Black and white photographs of Cashin's ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor., June - July 1979; 17 photographs (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor developed for press releases., 1979; 23 illustrations (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, Spring 1980 collection. Folder 1 of 2., June - July 18, 1979; 22 illustrations (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Russell Taylor, numbered 45 - 76, Spring II 1980 collection., August 14 - September 27, 1979; 30 illustrations (Box 56, Folder 1)